A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development (OD), South and Southeast Asia (SSEA), Burma Office Program Files FA585
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development (OD), South and Southeast Asia (SSEA), Burma Office Program Files
1952-1964
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA585
15.72 Cubic Feet 12 record storage boxes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Contains general correspondence, administrative records, accounting records, and documentation of program planning, program actions and payments.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation's office in Rangoon, Burma (Yangon, Myanmar) operated between 1953 and 1962. By the time the office closed, the Foundation had spent $7.7 million for programming in the country. Grantmaking primarily consisted of support for institution and capacity building in technical education and agriculture. The Burma program also issued some culture related grants.
Burma was part of the Ford Foundation's earliest efforts in overseas development in Asia. Together with India, Pakistan, and Indonesia, Burma was one of the first four country programs the Foundation established in Asia between 1952 and 1953. John Everton served as the Foundation's first Representative for Burma. Everton would later become the United States Ambassador to Burma and would serve in that position at the time that the Foundation left the country. Everton was succeeded in his post as Representative by Edwin G. Arnold (1956-1960) and then Walter A. Rudlin (1960-1962).
The Ford Foundation started to reduce assistance to Burma in 1960 and began shifting its overseas development efforts from a country approach to a regional program for Southeast Asia. Burmese General Ne Win took control of the Burmese Government in the 1962 Burmese coup d'etat. In April 1962, the Burmese Government informed the Ford Foundation that it had six months to remove its advisors from the country and that Burma no longer wished to receive assistance from the Foundation. The Foundation closed its Rangoon office by July 1962, and Rudlin relocated to Ford's office in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. The Foundation had prepared for this move from before the Burmese Government issued its order. Several other foreign organizations were expelled from Burma at the same time as the Ford Foundation.
- Information taken from Burma, Indonesia, and more Southeast Asia, a chapter in the Ford Foundation international history, Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 (FA739E), Report 013648.
- 53-152 Institute of Advanced Buddhistic Studies, 1953-1961 (Box 1)
- 54-61 State Agricultural Institute, 1953-1961 (Box 1)
- 54-103 Technical Institute in Burma, 1954-1961 (Box 1)
- 56-38 Consulting and Training Services in Government Management Accounting, 1955-1960 (Box 1)
- 56-115 Rangoon Technical High School, 1955-1958 (Box 1)
- 56-257 Business Administration Program, 1956 (Box 1)
- 57-11 Support for a Public Administration Library, 1955-1961 (Box 1)
- 57-95 Support for Burma Translations Society Development Program, 1956-1960 (Box 1)
- 57-102 Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development, 1958-1960 (Box 1)
- 57-316 Support for Girl Guide Association of Burma, 1957 (Box 1)
- 57-360 Adviser (Martens) and Training Equipment for Vocational Agriculture, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
- 58-57 Support for Adviser on Technical and Vocational Education, 1957-1960 (Box 1)
- 58-68 Training of Economic Development Planning Personnel, 1957-1963 (Box 1)
- 58-146 Training in Educational Administration, 1957-1963 (Box 1)
- 58-162 Science Teaching Program at University College Mandalay, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
- 58-292 Social Sciences Library University of Rangoon, 1958-1963 (Box 1)
- 58-314 Fellowships and Training in Public Administration and Management, 1958-1963 (Box 1)
- 59-12 Science Teaching Program Kambawsa College, 1958-1963 (Box 1)
- 59-32 Rural Youth Exchange Program, 1958-1961 (Box 1)
- 59-96 Pilot Project in Supervised Credit, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
- 59-317 University of Mandalay Library, 1959-1963 (Box 1)
- 59-381 Teaching and Research in Statistics and Agriculture Economics, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
- 59-392 General Program -- Burma Law Institute, 1958-1963 (Box 1)
- 60-464 Faculty of Agriculture -- University of Mandalay, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
- 61-78 Administrative Law Consultant for the Burma Law Institute (Gerard Moran), 1961-1962 (Box 1)
- 61-120 Program Specialist on Agricultural Education and Development (Gamble), 1961 (Box 1)
- 61-273 Vocational Technical Education in Burma (Dunwoody), 1961-1963 (Box 1)
- Ford Foundation Burma Reports (1/2), 1952-1961 (Box 1)
- Ford Foundation Burma Reports (2/2), circa 1965 (Box 1)
- Burma Grant Reports, 1961-1964 (Box 1)
- Burma Program Letters no. 1-20, 1953-1956 (Box 1)
- Burma Program Letters no. 21-32, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
- Ford Foundation Program in Burma, 1952-1963 (Box 1)
- File Directory, 1962 (Box 1)
- Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development -- Program Actions and Payments, 1957-1960 (Box 2)
- Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2)
- Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2)
- Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2)
- Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2)
- Advisor on Agricultural Education and Development -- Agricultural Reports 1 - 9, 1957-1959 (Box 2)
- FAO Conference on Agricultural Marketing -- Program Actions and Payments, 1959 (Box 2)
- FAO Conference on Agricultural Marketing -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2)
- Program Specialist in Agriculture (Gamble) -- Program Actions and Payments, 1961 (Box 2)
- A Report on Agricultural Education -- Faculty of Agriculture, 1959 September 16 (Box 2)
- Agriculture -- General, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
- In-Service Training in Agriculture -- General Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
- Agricultural Reports, 1961 (Box 2)
- Burma -- Agricultural Projects, 1960 (Box 2)
- Audio-Visual Education -- Program Action and Payments, 1954-1957 (Box 2)
- Audio-Visual Education -- General Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 2)
- Audio-Visual Education -- General Correspondence, 1954-1958 (Box 2)
- Basic Documents, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- Program Actions and Payments, 1956-1961 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2)
- Burma Girl Guides -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- Program Actions and Payments, 1956-1961 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3)
- Business Administration -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- Program Actions and Payments, 1955-1957 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3)
- Economic Research Project -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- Program Actions, 1958-1961 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3)
- Educational Administration Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 3)
- Economic Development Planning -- Program Actions, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
- Economic Development Planning -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3)
- Economic Development Planning -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 3)
- Economic Development Planning -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3)
- Economic Development Planning -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3)
- Fellowships in Economic Development Planning -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 3)
- Fellowships, FAO Short Course, Phillipines -- U Maung Gale and U Than Shwe, 1958 (Box 3)
- Ford Fellows, Burma -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3)
- Ford Fellows, Burma -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- Program Actions, 1954-1961 (Box 3)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 3)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 3)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 3)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 3)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 4)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 4)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence (1/2), 1959 January-June (Box 4)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence (2/2), 1959 July-December (Box 4)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4)
- Government Technical Institute (GTI) -- Information Copies, 1960 August-December (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- Program Actions, 1956-1958 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4)
- Burma Historical Commission -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4)
- Burma Law Institute (BLI) -- Program Actions, 1957-1961 (Box 4)
- Burma Law Institute (BLI) -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4)
- Burma Law Institute (BLI) -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 4)
- IIABS -- Program Actions, 1953-1961 (Box 4)
- Local Consultant -- Merillat, 1959 (Box 4)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- Program Actions, 1955-1960 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5)
- Local Government Consulting Services -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5)
- Advanced Management Program -- Program Actions, 1956-1960 (Box 5)
- Advanced Management Program -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5)
- Advanced Management Program -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 5)
- Advanced Management Program -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5)
- Advanced Management Program -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5)
- Advanced Management Program -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- Program Actions, 1955-1960 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5)
- Management Accounting -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5)
- University of Mandalay Library -- Program Actions, 1959-1961 (Box 5)
- University of Mandalay Library -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5)
- University of Mandalay Library -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5)
- University of Mandalay Library -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 5)
- University of Mandalay Library -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 5)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- Program Actions, 1954-1962 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 6)
- Mass Education Council (MEC) -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 6)
- Ministry of National Planning, 1956 (Box 6)
- Ministry of National Planning, 1957 (Box 6)
- Ministry of National Planning, GUB, 1958 (Box 6)
- Ministry of National Planning, GUB, 1995 (Box 6)
- Nutrition Laboratory -- Program Actions, 1955-1957 (Box 6)
- Nutrition Laboratory -- General Correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area I -- General, 1958 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area I -- General, 1959 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area I -- General, 1960 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area I -- General, 1961 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area I -- General, 1962 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area II -- General, 1957; prior years (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area II -- General, 1959 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area III -- General, 1957; prior years (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area III -- General, 1958 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area III -- General, 1959 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area III -- General, 1960 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area IV -- General, 1957; prior years (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area IV -- General, 1958 (Box 6)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area IV -- General, 1959 (Box 7)
- Overseas Development (OD) Area IV -- General, 1960 (Box 7)
- Overseas Development (OD) Training Associates, General Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
- Overseas Development (OD) Office, Ford Foundation New York, General, 1962 (Box 7)
- Office Space, Burma, 1954-1962 (Box 7)
- Program Descriptions, Ford Foundation Burma, 1956-1961 (Box 7)
- Program Grant Procedures, Ford Foundation, 1955-1961 (Box 7)
- Program Specialists, Burma, 1954-1957 (Box 7)
- Internship in Public Administration and Law -- Program Actions, 1960 (Box 7)
- Internship in Public Administration and Law -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- Grant Actions, 1956-1962 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Library -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- Program Actions, 1958-1962 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 7)
- Public Administration Training -- University of Rangoon, 1958 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- Program Actions, 1959-1961 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- C.E.W. Daniel (Harvard), 1958-1959 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- U Win Pe, 1957-1959 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- U Ba Than, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- General (Harvard), 1961 (Box 7)
- Public Service Fellowships -- General (Williams College), 1961 (Box 7)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- Program Actions, 1955-1961 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence (1/2), Jan-Jun 1960 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence (2/2), Jul-Dec 1960 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 8)
- Rangoon Technical High School (RTHS) -- Technical High School Project Terminal Report, Sep 30, 1962 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- Program Actions, 1958-1962 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 8)
- Research and Training in Economics, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 8)
- Science Teaching, Kambawsa College -- Program Actions, 1957-1961 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Kambawsa College -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Kambawsa College -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Kambawsa College -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Kambawsa College -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Kambawsa College -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- Program Actions, 1957-1961 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Photographs of Trees, 2012:033:002 (Box SF 1)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 9)
- Science Teaching, Mandalay -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 9)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- Program Actions, 1956-1962 (Box 9)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 9)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 9)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 9)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence (1/2), 1958 January-June (Box 9)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence (2/2), 1958 July-December (Box 10)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 10)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 10)
- Sarpay Beikman Institute (SBI) -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- Program Actions, 1955-1959 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 10)
- Small Industries -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- Program Actions, 1954-1961 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Chit Ko Ko, 1955-1959 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Hla Ohn, 1959 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Ba Thein, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Khin Maung Soe and U Mu, 1961 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Mya Than, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Thaung Tin, 1958-1960 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Tun Myint and U Than Sein, 1958-1961 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Thaung Nyunt, 1958 (Box 10)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Tun Kyine, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Ohn Maung, 1957-1960 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) Fellowships -- U Than Pe and U Ba Thein, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- India Study Tour, 1955 October (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- India and Pakistan Study Tour, 1956 November (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- India Study Tour, 1957 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- Philippines Study Tour, 1954 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- Philippines Study Tour, 1955 (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- Philippines Study Tour, 1958 May (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- Philippines Study Tour, 1958 September (Box 11)
- State Agricultural Institute (SAI) -- U Soe Study Tour, 1955-1956 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- Program Actions, 1958-1960 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 11)
- Social Science Library, University of Rangoon -- General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 11)
- Supervised Credit -- Program Actions, 1958-1961 (Box 11)
- Supervised Credit -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 11)